welcome brothers and sisters to another
Wednesday question and answer will we
open up with the Ten Commandments that
God commanded the whole world to keep
brother James yes sir and God spake all
these words saying I am the Lord thy God
which have brought thee out of the land
of Egypt out of the house of bondage
Thou shalt have no other gods before me
thou shall not make unto thee any Graven
image or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above
or is in the earth beneath or that is in
the water under the Earth Thou shalt not
bow down thyself to them nor serve them
for I the Lord thy God am a jealous God
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me
and showing Mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my Commandments
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain
for the Lord will not hold him Guiltless
that taketh his name in vain remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy six days
shalt thou labor and do all thy work but
the seventh day is the Sabbath of the
Lord thy God in it Thou shalt not do any
work thou nor thy son nor thy daughter
thy manservant nor thy maid servant nor
thy cattle nor thy stranger that is with
within thy Gates for in six days the
Lord made Heaven and Earth the sea and
all that in them is and rested the
seventh day wherefore the Lord blessed
the Sabbath day and hollowed it honor
thy father and thy mother that thy days
May beong upon the land which the Lord
thy God giveth thee Thou shalt not kill
Thou shalt not commit adultery Thou
shalt not steal thou shallal not bear
false witness against thy neighbor Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's wife
nor is man's servant nor is maid servant
nor his Ox nor his ass nor anything that
is thy
neighbors I read Exodus 20: 1-1 17 may
the Lord add a blessing to the reading
of this word in Jesus name we pray amen
amen so here on question and answer you
can ask us a question and we'll answer
the according to the King James Bible
and if we cannot find the answer we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time keep in mind that
all vague questions will not be answered
and all long scripture questions will
not be answered for time sake but we may
be able to point you in the direction of
a DVD or CD that you can purchase by
calling office so please be as direct as
possible with your questions so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible no
other Bibles will be acknowledged on
this program also keep in mind that this
is a live stream and you may begin to
send in your questions at this time even
questions that pertain to everlasting
life we just asking that you keep your
questions to a two scripture maximum but
let me introduce you to family that be
taking part in the panel this evening we
got brother
Jerome Grace and peace Brother Julius
good evening everybody brother Dre good
evening brother James good evening
everyone sister Deborah good evening
brother Sean good evening and we have
the guest caller with us and I'm brother
Cornell sister Deborah let us begin with
our first
question of the evening uh okay uh yes
there are several questions that will be
answered first before getting into
tonight's Q&A
the jar related as in Matthew 2: 29 and
10 what is this star seen in
Bethlehem all right well I'm go to
Matthew 2
James and let's see what is this star
that's in
Bethlehem Matthew 2 pick it up at verse
n and 10 then we go open it up to the
panel when they had I'm when they had
heard the king they departed and lo the
star which they saw in the East went
before them till it came and stood over
where the young child was and when they
saw the star they rejoiced with
exceeding great joy all right this star
here appears to be an angel open to the
panel okay I have it that's exactly
an
yep the angels are sto let's go into
job job the 38th
chapter 38
1-7 Job 38 1-7 then the Lord answered
job out of the Whirlwind and said who is
this that darkeneth counsel by words
without knowledge G up now thy loins
like a man for I will demand of thee and
answer thou
me where was thou when I laid the
foundations of the earth declare if thou
had
understanding who hath laid the measures
thereof if thou knowest or who has
stretched the line upon it whereupon are
the foundations thereof fastened or who
laid the Cornerstone thereof when the
morning Stars sang together and all the
sons of God shouted for joy or who shut
up the sea with doors when it Break
Forth as if it would had issued out of
the
womb now he said here who you know who
did all this you know when the morning
Stars saying and the sons of God shout
for Joy these morning Stars these are
angels okay and all the creation was
going on they were shouting and singing
and it show you that they are indeed
Angels let's go into
Revelation first
chapter we're going to first read 10 to
13 then we're going to skip
down Revelation 1 10 through1
13 uh I was in I was in the spirit on
the Lord's day and heard behind me a
great voice as of a trumpet saying I am
Alpha and Omega the first and the last
and what thou seest write in a book and
send it unto the seven churches which
are in Asia unto Ephesus and unto smura
and unto pergamos and unto thara and
unto Sardis and unto Philadelphia and
unto Leo
DEA and I had turned to see
the I'm at verse
12 go ahead and I turned to see the
voice that spake with me and being
turned I saw seven golden candlesticks
and in the midst of the seven
candlesticks one like unto the son of
man clothed with a garment down to the
foot and Girt about the paps with a
golden girdle and his and his okay get
down to verse uh
16 and he had in his right hand Seven
Stars and out of his mouth with a sharp
with a went a sharp two-edged sword and
his countenance was as the sun shineth
in his
strength now let's skip down to verse 20
let's see what these Seven Stars are
verse 20 The Mystery of the Seven Stars
which thou sawest in my right hand and
the Seven golden candlesticks the Seven
Stars are the Angels of the seven
churches and the Seven candlesticks
which thou s are the seven
churches so these are the Angels of the
seven churches as he would go on he said
to the angel of the Church of pramos and
the angel of the Church of Leo deia so
the angels are called Stars so this
Angel uh uh that went out there and led
them Shepherds that star that stood over
there where Jesus was being born was an
angel he was the one that guided them uh
to the manger that's all I have to say
all right hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next
question uh yes micia cure asked in John
1 verse 33 who sent John to baptize with
water also in Genesis 1 verse3 who said
let there be light God the father or
Jesus all right look like we got some
baptism and who said let there be like
uh brother Julius what you say let's go
uh brother James 1
and33 okay I'm there who sent John to
baptize in water let's look at what the
book
say 1 and33 go ahead and I knew him not
but he that sent me to baptize with
water the same said unto me upon whom
Thou shalt see the spirit descending and
remaining on him the same as he which
baptizes with the Holy Ghost now let's
see who sent him let's see who sent John
back up and read verse
six there was a man sent from God whose
name was John there was a man sent from
who from God whose name was John God
sent John to baptize with water and to
make straight the way of the Lord and
this is Jesus how do we know that
because John says something here
John says something here skip down to
verse verse
8 he was not that light but was sent to
Bear witness of that light uhhuh verse
um verse
15 John John be witness of him and cried
saying this was he of whom I spake he
that cometh after me is preferred before
me for he was before me Jesus before he
came in the flesh was
God he was God but he put off that that
Spirit body and came through Mary that's
why we at the Israel God always say
Jesus came through Mary he didn't start
at Mary he came through Mary that's why
John say he was before me so the answer
is Jesus was the one that sent uh sent
John to baptize with water and make
straight and John said I baptize you
with water Jesus gonna baptize you with
the Holy Spirit and let's go to Genesis
chapter one the second part of that
question who said let there be light God
the father or the son let's go to
Genesis 1 and read verse three Genesis 1
and3 when you get it brother James go
ahead and God said let there be light
and there was light now let's go to
Isaiah 45 Isaiah 45
set it up real good and then we going to
take you to John and one Isaiah 45 and
when you get it brother read verse 7 for
me please verse seven yep I form the
light and create Darkness uhuh I I make
peace and create evil I the Lord do all
these things oh so the Lord this is the
Lord who did this now John 1 and one
let's get let's get let's see who this
Lord is John 1 and one St John 1 and one
go ahead we going one to three go ahead
in the beginning was the word and the
Word was with God and the Word was God
so we got two beings we got two beings
that occupy that share the title of God
the father and the son go ahead the same
was in the beginning with God all all
things were made by him and without him
was not anything made that was made so
Jesus is the one that made everything
he is the one that said let there be
light he is the one that said let the
Earth bring forth this and let the Earth
bring forth that he is the one that gave
you the Sabbath day so he's the
orchestrator of
everything and he said all things were
made by him and without him was not
anything made that was made that was
Jesus the Christ I hope that helped yes
sir indeed that was the one that you
said came before John right that's right
he was in the beginning with God yes all
right thank you thank you for that
brother hope that answer their question
as we keep on moving yes and the time is
7:45 Zion asks for you to explain John 5
verse 43 who is the name that they will
receive if another shall come yes John 5
receive if another shall come in his own
name some say is the name
Jesus what you say Dre let's go to that
John five and we gonna read
uh verse
43 John 5 and 43 when you get it go
ahead and read it James I am come in my
father's name and ye receive me not if
another shall come in his own name him
ye will receive so who is it that they
will receive because they not receiving
Jesus he just said if another will come
in his own name him you will receive he
said I come in my father's name and you
receive me not so any Joe Blow that come
along They will receive him but they
will not receive Jesus but let's look at
that this is what they like let's go to
Isaiah 30th chapter and we're GNA pick
it up at verse eight Isaiah 30 and in
verse 8 when you get it go ahead and
read it
brother now go write it before them in a
table and note it in a book that it may
be for the time to come forever and
ever go ahead that this is a rebellious
people lying children children that will
not hear the law of the Lord so they
didn't want to hear the law of the Lord
and and that John 5 and 43 before that
in verse 39 he says search the
scriptures for in them you think you
have eternal life but they are they
which testify me but they wouldn't come
to
him that they might have life go ahead
read the next verse brother which say to
the seers see not and to the prophets
prophesy not unto us right things speak
unto us smooth things prophesy side
deceits so whoever does that that's who
they will hear they like that tell us
smooth things prophesy deceits but this
is not talking about Jesus in John 5 and
43 because they would not receive him
this is talking about any Jo blow that
come along not talking the word of God I
hope that that
helps all all right good point brother
hope that answered their question as we
continue to move on yes time 7:48 Roger
D Haynes asks on a regular Sabbath day
can you have wine with your meal at
evening Friday night at dark so once the
Sabbath kick in can you have wine with
your meal guess
caller there's no scripture in the Bible
that say you
can't because my wine uh uh can be you
is sometime is used as a part of the
dinner there ain't no scripture say that
say you
can't that's all I have to say about all
right we gonna keep it moving sister
Deborah to our next question yes most
love says whenever I'm around certain
people and I start talking about the
Bible
why do they try to change the subject or
pick up their phones and start playing
Facebook or Tik Tock videos it really
hurts all right well they really don't
want to hear what you have to say and
sometimes you're in a situation just
like that and you've been you you're
being Sanctified set apart they don't
want to hear the word hey that is a
choice I hear people all the time saying
don't talk religion politics and
sometimes you find yourself in an
environment with that you should respect
that let's go into um Titus the third
chapter Titus
3 because if you don't be if you keep
trying to force the issue then they may
start verbally hurting your feelings
rather than just going on Facebook and
all these other things once you get to
talking Titus
3 and let's pick it up at at verse
10 a
man a man that is in heretic after the
first and second admonition reject so if
you got somebody that don't want to hear
this word and you don't went to him the
first time and maybe the second and they
don't want to hear it leave him
alone because you can't make nobody hear
this word and you can't make nobody
serve God so if they don't want to hear
you talking turn over to Romans 14 then
you have to back up it's in your heart
to pray for them pray that they see the
light but you can't make them and U
saying that it hurt hey most of the
people you see on this panel we have
been through that with either friends or
family so that's nothing new to the game
but Romans 14 when you get there
brother pick it up at verse five go
ahead one man esteemeth one day above
another another other esteemeth every
day alike let every man be fully
persuaded in his own mind yeah you got
to be fully persuaded sometime you talk
to people don't want to hear nothing and
they are fully persuaded in their own
mind that they don't want to serve God
skip down to verse seven and eight and
this is where you have to leave them at
go ahead for none of us liveth to
himself and no man dieth to himself for
whether we live we live unto the Lord
and whether we die we die unto the Lord
whether we live therefore or die we are
the Lord and that's where you have to
leave that at sometimes so they don't
want to hear what you have to say and
you say it's hurting then you're just
going to have to deal with that part and
respect the fact that they don't want to
hear
it all right that's all I
got and uh we hope that that uh answered
your question as we move on to our next
moving on crystal Williams asked in
Revelation 1 verse 18 what is Jesus
saying when he says he has the keys to
hell and death so hell is a state of
condition so how did he have the keys to
hell all right we know he got the keys
to hell and death what else you got to
say brother
Jerome well hell you right it is to
state of condition and in this case hell
uh is the grave and he got the keys to
the grave and he got the keys to death
let's let's go take a look at um St John
chapter
5 and read verse 25- 29 and then we
gonna go to Deuteronomy after
that St John chapter 5 verse 25-
29 verily verily I say unto you the hour
is coming and now is when the dead shall
hear the voice of the Son of God and
they shall hear and they that hear shall
live for as the father hath life in
himself so hath he given to the son to
have life in himself and have given him
authority to execute judgment also
because he is the Son of
Man Marvel not at this for the hour is
coming coming in which all that are in
the graves shall hear his voice and
shall come forth and they that have done
good unto the resurrection of life and
they that have done evil unto the
resurrection of
damnation okay let's
um TI Deuteronomy
32 read verse one then we going to skip
to verse
39 Deuteronomy 32
yeah verse one and then skip to verse 39
to verse 39 okay give ear oh ye heavens
and I will speak and hear o Earth the
words of my
mouth see now that I even I am he and
there is no God with me I kill and I
make a lie I wound and I heal neither is
there any that can deliver out of my
hand
yeah so for those reasons he got the
key the death so
Revelation yeah so what about uh reading
Revelation 1 verse
18 yeah go ahead and read
that I am he that liveth and was dead
and behold I am alive forever more amen
and have the keys of hell and of death
that's all I got on that's right yes sir
even say The Last Enemy he's going to
destroy is death right brother Jerome
yep all right thank you brother for that
as we continue to keep on moving yes
Phyllis Campbell asked for you to
explain
Ecclesiastes 9 vers 7 and 8 let not thy
head lack no
ointment all right 9 7-8 brother Julius
what you say let's go there brother
James I'm there Ecclesiastes 9 and now
this is the behavior while we in this
Flesh and Blood body that we should be
operating in so this is what uh Solomon
is trying to get us to understand why we
in this Flesh and Blood body and our
attitudes and how we should be living
Our Lives go ahead verse seven go thy
way eat thy bread with joy and drink thy
wine with with a merry heart for God now
accepteth thy Works go ahead let thy
garments be always white let thy
garments let thy garments be always
white white in the Bible represents
righteousness it represents
righteousness in other words let your
garments always uh be right how do you
do that you keep the Commandments of God
that is the righteousness of God his
Commandments laws and statutes what's
the end of that and let thy head lack no
ointment ointment represents
consecration or someone being set apart
like when like when uh uh the sister
anointed Jesus with the uh with the with
the precious ointment and because he was
being set apart for something that he
was going to go through so if the
ointment shows favor like when David's
an anointed that's the favor uh uh
that's when you have favor with God
that's what that ointment represents so
he said let th head lack no ointment in
other words stay in God's favor stay in
God's favor I hope that helped anybody
want to add to
that best place to be Julius in God's
favor yep be righteous and stay in God's
favor that's it yeah all right thank you
for that brother we're gonna keep moving
to our next question yes Stephen G is
asked when Jesus was growing up did he
have have to learn the word of God or
did he already know and was waiting for
the time to start his
ministry all right guest caller can
share some
light I missed that which one was
it um St go yes uh Stephen googus asked
when Jesus was growing up did he have to
learn the word of God or did he already
know and was waiting for the time to
start his
ministry okay I I wasn't uh given this
question but I'll deal with it don't you
find in scripture where it says that uh
Lord gave him gave him Spirit without
limitation somebody run that down right
quick the one that say gave him Spirit
without
measure
[Music]
uh all right we search mode for that
she'll be coming up with that very
[Music]
shortly all right um
still looking we will find
it John 3 try John
3 okay try St John
3 and verse 34 I'm hoping that's it
right off the bat yeah that's it that's
it Jud John 3 and
34 3 and 34
for he whom God has sent speaketh the
words of God for God giveth not the
Spirit by measure unto
him see this is talking about Jesus when
he sent him he didn't put no limitation
he already knew and give you another
thing somebody go right quick to where
Jesus was having a discussion with the
elders they asking and answering
questions yeah when he was when he was
12 years old right
[Music]
all
right that's Matthew 21 and
uh verse
23 Matthew
21 verse 23 yeah that's I believe that's
it okay shout out and when he was coming
to the temple the chief priests and the
Elders of the people came unto him as he
was teaching and said by what Authority
do does US thou not that
one he was 12 years
old that's Luke two and Luke 2 and verse
42 Luke 2 Luke let's go
there yeah Luke 2 and verse 42 I am
there and when he was 12 years old they
went up to Jerusalem after the and the
after the custom of the
feast keep reading go Y and when they
had fulfilled the days as they returned
the child jesus carried behind in
Jerusalem and Joseph and his mother knew
not of
it but they but they
supposing him to have been in the
company went a Day's Journey and they
sought him among their k folk an
acquaintance and when they found him not
They Carried back again to Jerusalem
seeking him and it came to pass that
after three days they found him in the
temple sitting in the midst of the
doctors both hearing them and asking
them
questions now that he was 12 years old
he's little dark this is do and not
talking about physical Darkness I'm talk
just talking about the do of the word of
God god of the law like some of the
modern day call himself Dr so and so so
and so so he was sitting in the middle
of these are the these are the people
that supposed been he the word of God
answering asking question but keep
reading and all that heard him were
astonished at his understanding and
answers and when they saw him they were
amazed and his mother said unto him son
why hast thou dealt with us Behold thy
father and I have sought thee Sorrowing
and he said unto them how is it that ye
sought me which ye not that I must be
about my father's
business he said now look he was dealing
with all these people he was ask Mama
let his wisdom and his understanding
these are the elders the big brain and
then when his mother asked him
about how is that you didn't know that I
you don't know that I have to be about
my father's business so no he didn't
start taught him he had that knowledge
when he was
born
yeah all right all right and guess guess
caller can we go another place can we go
to Luke Luke uh
one what was that again Luke one Luke 1
and then and Luke one because it say
something uh about because I piggyback
on what the guest caller said he said
this about John cuz John was full of the
spirit Luke 1 verse
80 Luke 1 and verse 80 yeah it reads and
the child grew and whacked strong in
spirit and was in the desert to the day
of his showing unto Israel that was John
the Baptist now go to
Luke 2 and
verse 52 pick it back on what the guest
caller said Luke 2 52 this time and
Jesus and increased in wisdom and
stature and in favor with God and man
yeah and verse 40 say he grew and waxed
great in spirit he gra in spirit filled
with wisdom pigy back off what the great
guest caller
said all right hope that answered your
question we gonna keep
moving yes Norman Nicks asked is
circumcision a
foreshadowing of the father's Kingdom
the eth day what about this circumcision
is that a foreshadow brother Julius
everything is a foreshadow uh uh among
the Lord's feast days they point to
something greater um circumcision the
COV let's go to Genesis 17th chapter
quickly and it is so important that you
be circumcised that the that the Lord
said must needs be
circumcised Genesis 7
we going to go to right verse 9 let's
get cut to the chase Genesis 17 verse
9 and God said unto Abraham Thou shalt
keep my Covenant therefore thou and thy
seed after thee in their Generations
uhuh this is my Covenant which ye shall
keep between me and you and thy seed
after thee every Manchild among you
shall be circumcised what you got to do
and ye shall circumcise the Flesh of
your foreskin and it shall be a token of
the Covenant betwix me and you go ahead
and he that is eight days old shall be
circumcised among you every man child in
your Generations he that is born in the
house or bought with money of the
stranger which is not of thy seed
continue to 14 he he that is born in thy
house and he that is bought with with
thy money must needs be circumcised and
my Covenant that's must needs is very
strong must needs be because the lord
gave this man seven days to be in his
flesh and blood body continue and my
Covenant shall be in your flesh for an
Everlasting Covenant and the
uncircumcised Manchild whose flesh of
his foreskin is not circumcised that
Soul shall be cut off from his people he
hath broken my Covenant so you take the
for skin and you uh have it circumcised
okay let's look at the real purose
behind this verse Ezekiel the 43rd
chapter we go 26 and 27
Ezekiel 43 and verse 26 and 27 must
needs
be go ahead seven days shall thy Purge
The Altar and purify it and they
consecrate themselves you set yourself
apart that's what that circumcision now
you in a covenant with God go ahead and
when these days are expired it shall
seven days are expired when them seven
days are expired go ahead it shall be
that upon the Eighth Day and so forward
the priest shall make your burnt
offerings upon the Altar and your peace
offerings and I will accept you sayeth
the Lord God because God don't know you
unless you enter a COV with him so yes
that circumcision the In the Flesh
represents the rolling back of the Flesh
in the father's Kingdom there will be no
flesh and blood so you got to must needs
be circumcised and keep all the
Commandments including circumcision so
that you could be accepted of the father
I hope that
helped hey J let's read one more I'm
sorry go ahead
guess first thing is in Revelation the
20th
chapter uh uh
it tells you that there was the white
Throne judgment ain't that correct yes
sir and oh so now uh that comes the
white Throne judge but come just before
the father's Kingdom go and read that a
little bit let's say they all Revelation
you want that Revelation 20 want start
at verse
[Music]
11 Revelation 20 and 11 and I saw a
great white throne and him that sat on
it for whom from whose face the earth
and the heaven fled away and there was
found no place for them and I saw the
dead small and great stand before God
and the books were open and another book
was open which is The Book of Life and
the dead were judged out of those things
which were written in the books
according to their
works and the and the Sea gave up the
dead which were in it and and death and
Hell delivered up and up the dead which
were in them and they were judged every
man according to their works and death
and hell were cast into the Lake of Fire
this is the second
death that mean the death had been
terminated okay go right in the 21st
chapter and here come the father scen 21
and
one and I saw a new Heaven and a new
Earth for the first Heaven and the first
Earth were passed away and there was no
more sea and I saw and I John saw the
holy city New Jerusalem coming down from
God out of Heaven prepared as a bride
adorned for her husband and I heard a
great voice out of Heaven saying behold
the Tabernacle of God is with men and he
will dwell with them and they shall be
his people
and God himself shall be with them and
be their
God go ahead and God shall wipe away all
all tears from their eyes and there
shall be no more death neither sorrow
nor crying neither shall there be any
more pain for the former things are
passed
away the big thing is there shall be no
more death this is the Father's Kingdom
why is it one last place let's go into
First
Corinthians 15th chapter and start I
think start around
49 okay First Corinthians 15 starting at
49 and as we have borne the image of the
Earthly we shall also bear the image of
the Heavenly now this I say Brethren
that flesh and blood cannot inherit the
kingdom of God neither doeth corruption
inherit
corruption
behold go ahead and read it behold I
show you a mystery we shall not all
sleep but we shall all be changed in a
moment in a twinkling of the eye at the
last Trump for the trumpet shall sound
and the dead shall be raised
Incorruptible and we shall be changed
so
now this is the Father's Kingdom
represent the E day it's like your
brother said after man God gave man
seven days after the seven days so with
there be no more flesh and blood so when
you get circumcised is on the E day that
represent the the rolling way of the
Flesh and the only thing is left now is
Spirit beings that's all I have to say
Amen yes
sir all right hope that ansers your
question as we move on to our next one
yes Zion asked are there such a thing as
Spirits I don't want to call it a ghost
but is it possible for something to be
in your presence that other people can't
see when I was young I experienced such
things all right why don't we open this
one up to the panel and uh
go right
ahead sure there such thing of the
spirit what you saw I don't know but
there are such things as Spirits first
let's go into St John 4 and read verse
24 John 4 and
24 God is a spirit and they that worship
Him must worship Him in spirit and in
truth so God is a SP
there was Jesus now let's go into
Hebrews the first chapter and read verse
7 Hebrews 1 and7 and of the angels He
saith who maketh his angels spirits and
his ministers a flame of
fire to all the angels of spirits the
the holy and
Unholy and that's what uh uh uh and
sometime you had these people are the SE
and uh uh
uh you know they deal with for
me let's go into 1 Chronicles the 10th
chapter and read verse
13 1 Chronicles
10 uhuh verse
13 10 and verse
13 so Saul died for for his
transgression which he committed against
the Lord even against the word of the
Lord which he kept not and also for
asking counsel of one that had a
familiar Spirit to inquire of
it okay A Familiar spirit is an evil
angel Holy Spirits are all those that
didn't follow Satan and God of the
spirit both Father and
Son don't not if you thinking about uh
dealing with a person or somebody's
ghost no uh-uh if you saw something or
something was in your presence it was
either it was when most likely an
Angel that's all I have to say all right
sister Deborah time check for our next
question yes the time is
8:15 nor is tape as so are there two
trees of life if so can you read that to
us gu Cara can you um expound on that
are there two trees of
life let's go to establish one first
let's go to Genesis the 2 chapter and
read verse
[Music]
9 Genesis 2 ver9 and out of the ground
made the Lord God to grow every tree
that is Pleasant to the sight and good
for food the Tree of Life also in the
midst of the garden and the tree of
knowledge of Good and
Evil okay so let's run this tree of life
down let's go to Genesis the 3 chapter
and read verse
22 to
24 and the Lord God said behold the man
has become as one of us to know good and
evil and now least he put forth his hand
and take also of the tree of life and
eat and live forever therefore the Lord
God sent him forth from the Garden of
Eden to till the ground from whence he
was taken so he drove out the man and he
placed at the east of the Garden of Eden
cherubims and a flaming sword which
turned every way to keep the way of the
Tree of
Life okay so let's see who is see who it
is that's sitting in the middle of the
tree of life let's go into Psalms 98 and
read verse
one Psalm
98 and verse
one oh sing unto the Lord a new song for
he has done marvelous things his right
hand and His holy arm have gotten him
the
victory wait a minute no
no uh did I say 98 yes sir but may maybe
it's
881 see what that sound
like oh you know what actually I believe
that is 99 and one it says the Lord reth
let the people tremble he sth between
the cherubims let the Earth be
moved okay still read 88 And1
okay and 88 And1 oh God oh Lord God of
my salvation I have cried day and night
before
thee oh no okay but the other one's
right he he the Lord God SED between the
cherubs but still there was another one
I like
better
98 where he said the Lord reigned he s
it between the
Sher yes 99 and
one 99 and one then read it the Lord
reth let the people tremble he sth
between the chims let the Earth be
moved so now who was the sheram
protecting tree of life and there's Lord
here that uh uh uh uh and a true life is
this Lord here is
Jesus because you ain't never dealt with
the father at any time or heard His
Voice or seen his shap so this
it was Jesus that the tree of that the
CH Angel was around that's why when they
build when they built the temple and the
Tabernacle they built a mercy seat put
it on top of the Ark of the Covenant and
The Mercy Seat is where the Lord said
and on each side of the ersy seat was
chair of angels let you know that the
chair of angels was there to protect the
way of the Lord the tree of life so now
that mean that he gives life list let's
see who else giv of life let's go to St
John the 5th chapter read verse 25 and
26 St John 5 ver 25 and
26 verily verily verily I say unto you
the hour is coming and now is when the
dead shall hear the voice of the Son of
God and they that hear shall live for as
the father hath life in himself so hath
he given to the son of son to have life
himself so now the father H is the tree
of life and the son is the tree of life
because both of them can give life so
yes there is two trees of Life the one
we dealt with directly and the one we
won't deal with until we shed this flesh
and blood for
him don't have yes call A Psalm 80 and
one is that other passage can you go
there and read
that
80 Psalm 80 and one yes give ear oh
Shepherd of Israel thou that leadest
Joseph like a flock thou that dwellest
between the cherubims shine
forth okay and other and other scripture
will tell you the Lord God that dwelleth
between the Cher that's Jesus that's the
tree of life so and he can give life and
the father can give life so yes two
trees of
Life all right thank you for that as we
continue to move on to our next yes uh
Rose Martin says if Esau is Semite and
he is not white then who are his present
day
descendants guess Calla
well who said you know when you start
white when you go into Genesis the 10th
chapter it called the son of japi
Gentiles didn't it
yeah do now and we know that that
represented the uh the uh largest body
of Gentiles but then Esau is a semantic
he come out he our twin brother who says
that God uh uh uh uh who says that he
can't be white
what color is Adam and
Eve nobody know we know one thing all of
the races come out of Adam and Eve isn't
that correct yep y all the colors that
come out of Adam and
Eve so when it's come to the word white
that's what people call people in the
light skin so when the statement is made
that is came noetic being white I said
this person takes too much on himself he
need to do some research erod according
to history was an Edomite yep
Herod was a converted Edomite the mbes
converted him his his
forefathers because they was in southern
Jerusalem and it named it aduma which is
Greek for
Edom he was his forefather was converted
and Herod was appointed by the Romans to
be king to be king over
Jerusalem and all you got to do is go
into history and look at Herod the Great
and you will call him white and so all
his descendants so these people that are
called Jews now the Lord identified them
as the Seed of Abraham and those that
say they are Jews and are not but do lie
they are semetic the children of Esau so
whoever this this person is that said K
might be white you need to do some
research that's all I have to say yeah
he turned white too didn't
he huh turned Miriam white for seven
days didn't he sure he did he did better
than that the Lord turned everybody all
these different covers look at the
Chinese
Mongolians Africans Gentiles the Lord
made them all you going what you going
to do is you going to tie the Lord's
hand that he can't do what he want to do
these people that are call theel Jews or
white they are the children of Esau your
twin brother and if you did a little
research then you wouldn't ask this
question that's all I have to say all
right we're gonna move on to our next
question yes moving on Miss way says
what does does First Corinthians 10
verse 24
mean 1 Corinthians 10 and 24 what does
it mean brother
Drey let's go to that First Corinthians
10 and read verse 24
brother goad let no let no man seek his
own but every man another's
wealth right it
says don't seek let no man seek his own
but every man another's
well in other words another man
another's well being are the good of
others skip down to verse
33 go even even as I please all men in
all things not seeking my own Prophet
but the prophet of many that they may be
saved yes sir notice it says prophit
there you know and wealth it uses those
words profit and wealth and they can be
associated with with money but it can
also be associated with your good or
your
well-being in Revelations 2 and9 it says
I Know Thy poverty and
tribulation yet Thou Art Rich what kind
of wealth or richness is he talking
about here but let's go look at another
place let's go to Revelations 3 and look
at that Revelations 3 and pick it up at
verse
17 Revelations 3 and
17 go ahead because thou sayest I am
rich and increase with goods and have
need of nothing and knowest not that
thou are wet wretched and miserable and
poor and blind and naked so if you got
material things and you don't have the
Lord
you are wretched miserable poor and
blind and naked Verse 18 go ahead I
counsel thee to buy of me gold tried in
the fire that thou mayest be rich and
white rment that thou mayest be closed
and that the shame of thy nakedness do
not appear and anoint thy eyes with eyes
sell that thou mayest see so he's
talking about a different kind of
clothing here just like in that first
Corinthians 10 he's talking about the
wellbe wealth or good of others right
there as we read in 1 Corinthians
10:24 and then bagged up in verse 33 so
I hope that that helps an to understand
that
question go ahead all right thank you
for that brother let's move on to our
next question sister yes brother Israel
ask is there such a thing as
righteous
pride no those two words shouldn't even
be used together Lord don't even don't
like Pride period so how you go put the
righteousness along with the pride but
let's go into um job 33 first job 33
because if if we are all filthy rags and
come out the dirt of the ground how can
you be so
prideful job 33 and14 go ahead let's see
what the Lord does with pride so he
don't have to hurt you go ahead for God
speaketh once yay twice yet man
perceiveth it
not in a dream in a vision of the night
when deep sleep falleth upon men and
slumbering upon the bed uhhuh then he
openeth the ears of men and Sealth their
instruction that mean that he may
withdraw man from his purpose and hide
Pride from man all right so the Lord
would hide Pride from man because he
don't care for that proud and arrogant
and all of that turn over to job 41
let's go there right
quick because those are the works and
attributes of Satan that have all this
pride and
arrogance and who is Satan here read
that verse 33 and
34 on the evil side of things go ahead
upon Earth there is not his like who is
made without fear he beholdeth all high
things he is a king over all the
children of Pride so it is that evil
side that got you thinking that being
prideful even if you want to put the
word rightous on it it don't fit let's
go on Proverbs 8 Proverbs the eth
chapter this be the last one Proverbs
8 yes sir some words just don't fit I
mean you know hard to tell a brother oh
you sure are clean and you sure are
dirty Proverbs 8
and let's pick it up at that verse four
and then we go to skip down Proverbs 8
and4 go ahead unto you oh men I call and
my voice is to the sons of man the Lord
want us to hear that skip down to verse
13 and go ahead the fear of the Lord is
to hate evil pride and arrogancy and the
evil way and the forward mouth do I hate
the the Lord say there that he want you
hey to hate evil hate Pride hate
arrogancy and if you're supposed to hate
those things can't put righteous in
front of it it doesn't exist not in the
eyes of the
Lord so that's all I
got and we hope that that answers your
question let us move on to our next one
sister yes we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday September the 11
2024 10 three MJ asks can we communicate
with those in the Lake of
Fire all right can we communicate with
those in the Lake of Fire Let's Open up
to the panel but let's go to Luke 16
James and let's see a conversation that
took
place Luke 16 you get that brother pick
it up that verse 19 and go
ahead there was a certain rich man which
was clothed in purple and fine linen and
fared sumptuously every day and there
was a certain beggar named Lazarus which
was laid at his gate full of swords and
Desiring to be fed with the crumbs which
fell from the rich man's table moreover
the dogs came and licked his swords
uhhuh and it came to pass that the
beggar died and was carried by the
Angels into Abraham's bosom the rich man
also died and was buried all right so
the rich man lat on he ended up in the
Lake of Fire and there's a conversation
taking place in verse 23 go ahead and in
hell he lifted up his eyes being in
torments and seeth Abraham a far off and
Lazarus in his bosom and he cried and
said Father Abraham have mercy on me and
send Lazarus that he may dip the tip of
his finger in water and cool my tongue
for I am tormented in this flame it's a
conversation taking place here between
Father Abraham and the rich man that was
in the Lake of Fire go ahead but Abraham
said Son remember that thou in thy
lifetime receiveth thy good things and
likewise Lazarus evil things but now he
is confronted and thou art tormented
so this is one conversation that we can
read about that took place um open to
the
panel you just answered the question all
right well we'll keep it moving on that
note hope that answered your question
next question sister yes moving on uh
read the Bible daily as in Matthew 9
verse 28 through 30 why did Jesus say in
verse 30 see that that no man knows
it all right Matthew 9
28-30 yes why don't we go there and then
the guest caller Shar some light on why
did Jesus say in verse 30 see that no
man know
it
goad and when he was come into the house
the Blind Men came to him and Jesus said
unto them believe ye that I am able to
do this they said unto him yay Lord then
touched he their eyes saying according
to your faith be it unto you and their
eyes were open and Jesus straightly
charged them saying see that man see
that no man know it
my answer is that is I don't know why he
said
that all right we'll leave it there and
we will move on to our next question yes
Jil Masters asked in Isaiah
42 uh
verse one and two is this the father
speaking about Jesus or Jesus speaking
about John the
Baptist all right Jerome share some
light on that
question no it's not talking about John
the Baptist there let's go read
it Isaiah 42
1-2 behold my servant who I uphold mine
elect in whom my soul delighteth I have
put my spirit upon him he shall bring
forth judgment to the Gentiles he shall
not cry nor lift up nor cause his voice
to be heard in the
street yeah so this is the Father's
servant okay and that servant is
actually Jesus read verse uh
three a bruised Reed shall he not break
and the smoking flax shall he not quench
he shall bring forth judgment unto
truth now let's go to the New Testament
and uh read verse uh chapter
12 verse 14- 21 Which
chapter uh chapter
12 of which book Matthews
okay Matthew 12
yeah and it up atse 14 and read it to
the
21 Matthew
12:14 then the Pharisees went out and
held a counsel against him how they
might destroy him but when Jesus knew it
he withdrew himself from then and great
multitudes follow him and he healed them
all and charged them that they should
not make him
known that it might be fulfilled which
was spoken by Isaiah the prophet saying
behold my servant who I have chosen my
beloved and whom my soul is well pleased
I will put my spirit upon him and he and
he shall show judgment to the Gentiles
he shall not strive nor cry neither
shall any man hear his voice in the
streets a bruised Reed shall he not
break and a smoking flax shall he not
quench till he send forth judgment unto
Victory and in his name shall the
Gentiles trust yeah so yeah that's
that's the father's servant now if you
want to say the father said Jesus
telling you what the father's saying
about him if you
will that's all I got
on all right we'll leave it there and
keep moving on to our next
question yes Ben F wants you to explain
Isaiah
verse3 he States it would appear that
hunting and burning insect
shouldn't be done please
explain all
right everything is not always as it
appears sometimes let's go to that
Isaiah 66 and let's open this up to the
pan Isaiah
66 yeah read three and four so we can
see that the Lord had a problem with the
people go ahead and then we open up to
the p
he that kth an ox is as if he slew a man
he that sacrificeth a lamb as if he cut
off a dog's neck he that offered an
oblation as if he offered swine's blood
he that burneth incense as if he blessed
an idol yay they have chosen their own
ways and their soul delighted in their
Abominations
Abominations I also will choose their
delusions and will bring their fears
upon them because when I called none did
answer when I spake they did not hear
but they did evil before my eyes and
chose that in which I delighted
not all headed open to the
panel gu caller you want to weigh in on
that all is really saying is this man uh
uh he uh uh draw near with the Lord to
the Lord with his mouth but he do his
own thing let's go Isaiah 29th chapter
and Ste read start reading at verse
29 verse
9 stay yourselves and wonder cry ye out
and cry they are drunken but not with
wine they stagger but not with strong
drink for the Lord have poured out upon
you the spirit of deep sleep and have
closed your eyes the prophets and your
rulers the seers hath he
covered and the vision and the vision of
all is become unto you as the words of a
book that is sealed which men deliver to
one that is learned saying read this I
pray thee and he saith I cannot for it
is
sealed and the book is delivered to him
that is not learned saying read this I
pray thee and he saith I am not
learned wherefore the Lord saith for as
much as this people draw near near me
with their mouth and with their lips do
honor me but have removed their heart
far from me and their fear to towards me
is taught by the precept of
men so in other words you know the ones
that the sacrificing we doing now this
man doing with his own wayes just like
sacrificing a dog uh uh some unclean
animal because uh he ain't teaching the
word of God no more because uh the seal
to him or even been taught by somebody
that don't can't read so what it being
taught to fear toward the lord is taught
by the precepts of men and that's just
like
sacrificing a dog that's all I to say
all right hope that answered your
question next question yes the air I
breathe ask is it okay to have
intercourse with your spouse during the
Sabbath oh it's not
okay have intercourse with your spouse
doing the
let's turn over to Isaiah
58 Isaiah
58 if you doing your own pleasure and
that is not right Isaiah 58 brother pick
it up at verse
13 if thou turn away thy foot from the
Sabbath from doing thine own pleasure or
from doing thy pleasure on my holy day
and call the Sabbath of delight the holy
of the Lord Lord honorable and shall
honor him not doing thine own ways nor
finding thine own Pleasures nor speaking
thine own words because you got six days
why you GNA pollute the Lord's Sabbath
day and do that it's not right it's evil
to do that read the next verse then
shalt thou Delight thyself in the Lord
and I will cause thee to ride upon the
high places of the earth and feed thee
with the heritage of Jacob thy father
for the mouth of the Lord has spoken
it that's all I
got I hope that that aned your question
we're gonna move to our next one with
the time J yes the time is
8:42 uh we can talk right here says is
there a difference in a spirit versus
Soul also if you're cremated does Jesus
still come to get you
well come get everybody open to the
panel yes there's a difference between
spirit and soul let's go to Ezekiel the
8th
chapter I'm Ezekiel uh the 20th chapter
18 18 Ezekiel
18 Man became a living Soul Flesh and
Blood he became a living Soul come from
the dust of the ground Ezekiel 18 and4
brother James Ezekiel 18
and4 behold All Souls are mine as the
soul of the father so also the soul of
the son is mine the soul that sinth it
shall die so Souls die Soul die read
verse
20 the soul that sinth it shall die the
son shall not bear the iniquity of the
father neither shall the father bear the
iniquity of the son the righteousness of
the righteous shall be upon him and the
wickedness of the wicked shall be upon
him now let's go to 1 Corinthians the
15th
chapter 1 Corinthians
15 uh let's see here ver Corinthians
15 and pick it
up at verse 51 even when the Lord
return go ahead look what Paul said
behold I show you a mystery we shall not
all sleep but we shall all be changed in
a moment in the twinkling of an eye at
the last Trump for the Trump shall sound
and the dead shall be raised
Incorruptible and we shall be changed go
ahead for this corruptible must put on
incorruption
and this Mortal must put on
immortality so when this
corruption so when this corruption shall
have put on incorruption and this Mortal
shall have put on immortality then shall
be brought to pass the same that is
written death is swallowed up in Victory
you take away death which is the grave
you come out and you resurrected or even
in the great right even when you get
your changeed body you cannot die Spirit
beings don't die that's why you can't
kill Satan the devil or his angels but
you can punish them
forever that's all I
got let me a couple let's go
Genesis read verse
7 and the Lord God formed man of the
Dust of the ground and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life and Man
became a living
Soul no that's that's when he that's
what we are we're living Souls let's go
into First Corinthians the 15th chapter
I think this is around 40th
verse think you can start reading
that First Corinthians 15 and
40 there are also celestial bodies I'm
sorry there are also celestial bodies
and bodies terrestrial but the glory of
the celestrial is one and the glory of
the terrestrial is another there is one
glory of the Sun and another glory of
the Moon and another glory for the stars
for one star differ from another star in
glory so all so also is the resurrection
of the dead it is sown in corruption it
is raised in corruption or I'm sorry it
is sown in corruption it is raised in
incorruption it is sown in dishonor it
is raised in glory it is sown in
weakness it is raised in power it is
sown a natural body it is raised a
spiritual body there is a natural body
and there is a spiritual
body and so it is written
the first man Adam was made a living
Soul the last Adam was made a quickening
spirit that's it go ahead how be it that
was not the fir that that was not first
which is spiritual but that which is
natural and afterward that which is
spiritual the the first man is of the
earth earthy the second man is of the
Lord From Heaven
but they sure there different bodies
Spirit a soul is flesh and
blood and the
spirit and the uh uh uh spiritual body
is is spirit so man is made a living
soul and Jesus once he come out the
grave he went back to being a Living
spirit there's a
difference yeah all those that get that
first resurrection Spirit also
[Music]
yeah and uh brother Cornell you stated
also because his uh other question was
if you were cremated does Jesus still
come to get you and you uh stated he
comes to get
everybody yes everybody nobody misses
out Prem Bones on the bottom of the
sea he's coming to get
everybody eaten up by alligators no
matter what no matter
what cannot escape and you can read that
in Revelation 20 and
17 about those in the
sea Revelation 20 and
13 and in ecclesiastics it say dust you
are and on the dust you will
return so you going to get raised from
the
dust yeah that is correct hey list let's
read that Dre that Revelation 20 and uh
13 there yes sir yeah let's read go
ahead brother Andrea if you want to ask
something go right ahead
brother and the Sea gave up the dead
which were in it and death and Hell
delivered up the dead which were in them
and they were judged every man according
to their works right so if you you
alligate a bait and you got ate up by
alligators and whatever the alligator
put out of him you going to get raised
from whatever that's right you are you
gonna get raised from that dust yes sir
all right hope that answers your
question is we move on to our
next next question Malik Shakur ask for
you to explain Matthew 8 verse 29 why
did they say say are Thou come hither to
come torment us before our time Matthew
8:29 they was dealing with the one that
had all that power but let's go and read
that and open it up to the
panel Matthew 8 and
29 and behold they and behold they cried
out saying what have we to do with thee
Jesus thou son Son of God aren Thou come
hither to torment us before the
time so these the evil angels we talking
about
here go
ahead and there was a good way off from
them and heard of many swine feeding so
the Devils besought him saying if thou
cast us out suffer us to go away into
the herd of Swan and he said unto them
go and when they were come out they went
into the herd of swine and beheld the
whole herd of swine ran violently down a
steep Place into the sea and perished in
the waters all right open to the
bth they use the word before the time
and you can go and read is first and
second Peter in Jude where he said that
they under chains of Darkness yeah
preserve until the day of judgment some
down 6 a but one chapter Jud verse 6
okay what's it
say get right there Jude
6 it says and the angels which kept not
the first estate but left their own
habitation he have reserved them
reserved in Everlasting chains unto
darkness and the judgment of the great
day so that's the time when they going
to be judged and
punished on Judgment Day so that's why I
say have you come to T men us before the
time they know that they going to the
leify and they know what time they going
to it and that wasn't the time that's
all I have to say all right so they're
already judged Cornell they just waiting
on the judgment
y y all right let us move on to our next
question sister Deborah as time is it
Tak yes Zion ask how do you know when
God has completely given up on
you when you hit that
reprobate God stamp rep probate on you
you are
finished open to the pth
but you don't know it but you don't know
it
yeah ain't no way to know
it yeah but if you uh if you do know
that you doing something you shouldn't
be doing then it's time to stop doing
that repent from it why you to do
so y y that's it
the nth chapter say long as you liveing
There's Hope yes sir y there's hope
that's for sure all right next question
next question Victoria Smith asked for
you to explain Jeremiah
28 vers 15-
17 Jeremiah
28 vers 15- 177
go there James I'm
there all right pick it up at that
verse 15 and read it through to the 17
and let's open it up to the
pan then the Prophet Jeremiah unto
hananiah the prophet here now hananiah
the Lord ha not sent thee but thou
makest this people to trust in a lie
therefore thus sayeth the Lord behold I
will cast thee from off the face of the
Earth this year Thou shalt die because
thou has taught Rebellion against the
Lord so haniah the prophet died the same
year in the seventh
month when you when you when you when
you off the face of the Earth you in the
ground that's
right ain't nothing to explain he just
said I'm gonna kill you yeah
and he said that in verse
17 died the same year so all right
sister de's time is ticking let's get a
few more
in all right uh Zion says in John 9
verses 1
through3 why did the disciples ask Jesus
was the blind man born that way because
of his sin how could he have sinned
before he was
born all right let's go there and read
that John
nine yes verses one through three all
right where here brother James let open
that up to the panel too and as Jesus
passed by he saw a man which was blind
from his birth and his disciples asked
him saying master who did Sin this man
or his parents
that he was born blind Jesus answered
neither have this man sinned nor his
parents but that the works of God should
be made manifest in him yes because he
got his sight back
panel some he got his sight couldn't get
it back he didn't have it but go ahead
brother what you say some things are
done for the glory of God to to make
people believe that's why Jesus said
this man didn't sin nor his parents but
that the works of God so to show that he
was the Christ cuz he came he said he
came to Open the Eyes of the blind make
the dumb to speak the lame to walk and
uh bring people back to the dead to
prove who he was and what was prophesied
about
him for the glory of
God
y i i want to simple it down a little
bit the question should have been asked
did this guy this guy that was born
blind did his parents sin because he
being a baby couldn't
sin excellent
point Y born blind and even even to this
day no one has ever received their sight
who was born
blind right but but if blind that wasn't
because he Sinn because if you how can
you sin be sin before you were born
right not
possible that's
right okay uh sister Deborah let's shoot
for one more and let's see what happened
go ahead all all right Dorothy griffi uh
says we have heard preachers other
Christians say when someone dies don't
worry you'll see your loved ones again
if we're if we're all be changed in the
twinkling of an eye how can people say
that is that
true yeah
you in the Kingdom God or in the Lake of
Fire he just gave something earlier
about Lazarus and the rich man you'll
see
him y that's right and question only me
mentioned the first resurrection
there'll be another one after
that either way it go you everybody
gonna live forever that's right it get
to see him
again all right sister Deborah how we
looking all right uh the time is 8:59 so
it's up to you all right one more let's
call it all right malici shur says will
all nations live together in the Kingdom
or will Nations have their own lands
living within each
other all
right gu call what you
say and it says in New Jerusalem and I
know Skip down where it say and the
Nations that are saved
yeah Revelations
21 mhm verse
24 read it all right and the nations of
them which are saved shall walk in the
light of it and the kings of the earth
do bring their Glory and Honor into it
that mean they going to be Nations and
going to be Kings the only difference is
they going to be immortal they going to
be holy and they will be
God yes
amen yep that is it all right we hope
that answered your question and sister
Deborah time Chad the time is nine
o'clock yes we have ran out of time we
want to thank everybody from all around
the world who tuned in with us this
evening and asked your questions and we
took joy in answering the ones that we
were able to and we thank you and we say
until we all come together again be safe
out there be blessed and may the Lord
have mercy on us all brother James Clos
us
out Our Father which art in heaven
Hallowed be thy name thy kingdom come
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our debts as we forgive
our debors and lead us not into
temptation but Deliver Us from Evil for
thine is the kingdom and the power and
the glory forever
in Jesus name